This is VOA news via remote timeless
US President Donald
Design a federal government funding package as of Sunday evening
That includes coronavirus relief money for struggling Americans
What the president did
Tweet that good news could be coming regarding The Cove Atlantis Dells
He said from his account
Information would follow
Without him signing the 2.3 trillion dollar spending package
The clock continues to
Take tours
Potential US Government shutdown
A partial shutdown
Could begin shortly after midnight on Sunday
Increase unemployment benefits in evictions protections also expired at midnight Sunday
President Trump had sharply criticized The Ledger
Gestation last week
And on Saturday indicated his continued objections to it
He tweeted he's still wanted most Americans receive $2,000 quote
Rather than the measly $600 that is now in the
Amass
Covid-19 vac
Maxine Drive began Sunday in Europe
Pensioners and Medics were the first lining up to get the shots and begin the end of the pandemic
That has crippled economies and taken lives around the world
The European region of 450 million people
Is trying to catch up with the United States
Jason Britton
We just started vaccinations within the last
Couple weeks
The European Union is due to receive
12.5 million doses by the end of the year
Enough to vaccinate more than six
.6
Million people
Based on the two
Ghost regiment
The companies are scrambling
Global demand
And aim to make 1.3 billion shots
Next year
South Africa's Health Ministry said the total number of coronavirus infection
Crossed 1 million on Sunday
That's since the country's first case in March
The Grim Milestone comes just nine days after the country reported 900000 cases
This is VOA news
Us investigators have named a person of interest in connection with Annex
Explosion
In the city of Nashville Tennessee on Christmas morning
They're investigating a 63 year old man named Anthony Warner
In connection with
The Christmas Dawn explosion that rock the commercial and tourist District
One Theory being explored is that an AT&T Communications building was targeted
Because the recreational vehicle was parked near it before the bomb went off
Gunfire
A scare tactic
Did not keep
Keep Central African Republic residents
From turning out in huge numbers to vote in the presidential and legislative elections on Sunday
That's according to the head of the UN mission
Rebel groups
Hostel 2 president
Austin
Account
Madera
Haven't carried out
Attacks and threatened to March
Cap the capital and disrupt the election
After the Constitutional court this month
Rejected several candidate
It's including former president Francois bozize
Madera
Is seeking a second term
Measure began counting votes for from an election
That's expected to lead the West African nation's first
Transfer of power
Between two democratically elected president
Results are expected in the coming days
Across the US
Native American tribes are working to Pro
Protect their oldest members from the Coronavirus
But the effort is more about is about more than just
Protecting lives
It's also about preserving culture
Tribal elders
Service honored link to the past and often possess unique knowledge
About language history and culture
That knowledge is
Is all the more valuable because tribes often passed down their Traditions orally
Tribal groups are Distributing protective gear
Delivering meals and racing to obtain vaccines for their eldest Generations
That includes the Navajo Nation in the Southwest
The Cherokee Nation in Oklahoma
The blackfeet nation in the state of Montana among others
A 6.8 magnitude earthquake struck off the coast of South Central Chile on Sunday
That's according to the European and Mediterranean seismology
A seismological
Seismological
Center
Chilean
Officials immediately discarded the risk
Have a tsunami
There were no initial reports of damage immediately following the earthquake
The strong tremor
Place to a depth of
Kilometer
According to the ER
MSC
We have more International
Headlines for you on voanews.com you can go there for the very latest
Peel remote
I'm Liz palka
VOA news