This is VOA news via remote on Diane Roberts
Top new coronavirus restrictions have begun in the UK with Scotland and Northern Ireland under tighter measures
To try to slow a new variant
Of the virus
That is believed to spread more quickly
AP correspondents area Shockley rapport
Measure the relaxer
Christmas day in Wells have also been imposed
The number of people under the country's top level of restrictions tier 4 has increased by 6 million to 24 million
People 3%
Population
No individual households is allowed and only Center
Travel permits
Jim's pools how dresses and stores selling non essential Goods
Have you ordered
To close
Soda Shaq
I'm done
The first two cases of that particularly infectious coronavirus variant
Haven't confirmed in Canada at healthy
Authorities said Saturday
The couple has been placed in isolation
It comes the same day Ontario re-imposed a lockdown
For several weeks
It's due to a spike in covid-19 cases
Swedish Elvis
Authorities announced
First isolated case
Of the new virus
Saying the supper or had travel
Call from the United Kingdom
But insisted the risk of spreading was low
Four cases
Confirmed in Madrid Saturday
Do the patients were not seriously ill
According to the Madrid Regional governments Deputy Health chief
Who said quote there is no need for alarm and quote
The new strain which experts fear is more contagious
Wanted more than 50
The countries to impose travel restrictions on the UK
Meantime in Asia
China's communist leadership issued a statement
Healing the quote extremely extraordinary glory and quote of its handling of the virus
That emerged in the countries
By province last year State News Agency reported
In the post-soviet nation of Turkmenistan where the government claims no coronavirus cases
The president
Family dentist
Claim that liquor
Could stop Coronavirus
From developing
This is VOA news
Saturday Britain and the European Union published
The full text of the post brexit Trade Agreement aimed at governing their relationship
When the UK
Definitively leave the block
Single Market in just 5 days
The document is more than 1200 pages long and lays out the
The tail on trade
Lawn Force
Stan and dispute settlement among other arrangement
The document is complex
And included
Explanatory notes
And side Arrangements on nuclear
Cooperation and the exchange of classified information
Even though the complexity both sides have indicated they will rush through its
Adoption
Law enforcement officials have told the Associated Press
Federal investigators have identified
Interest
In connection with the explosion that rocked downtown Nash
Asheville in the US state of Tennessee Christmas Day
AP correspondent Julie Walker
Reports investigators from multiple Federal and local law enforcement agencies were at a home and Antioch and Suburban
Nashville after receiving information relevant to the investigation
According to FBI special agent Jason pack another law enforcement official speaking on the condition of anonymity
Told the Associated Press
Investigators regard someone associated with the property as a person of interest in the bombing
Earlier Saturday investigators said they were looking at a number of individuals
Maybe connected to the bombing
But I've also found no additional explosive devices
The blast was Roxanne AT&T building also knocked out some 911 cell and Wi-Fi communication
Across the
The state
Anjali Walker
US President Donald
Trump the spending the holiday weekend at his Florida Resort
As both Democrat
Iten Republican
We need to see whether he will sign a critical pandemic relief and government funding package
That he sharply criticized
Earlier this week
The legislation which includes 892 billion dollars
Coronavirus relief
Was flown from Washington to the Presidents Mar-A-Lago
Club in Palm Beach Florida
For him to sign into law
But the present surprise lawmakers and both parties
By labeling the legislation a disgrace
Mr. Trump said the package gave too much money to special
Interest in foreign aid
And said direct payment
Length of $600 for most American
Should be increased
2 $2,000
A partial federal government shutdown Looms
Early Tuesday
If Miss
Trump is not sign the bill
Congress is planning to
Return to work Monday and could take up a stop-gap measure
To extend Government funding
George Blake with
Was the last in the line of British spies who
Secret work for the Soviet Union
Humiliated the intelligence and stylish
Discovered at the height of the
The Civil War
He died in Russia
Saturday
He was 98
From Washington
Buy remote
I'm dying Robert
VOA news